EMILY DOWNEY WEB DEVELOPER

PERSONAL PROFILE

Web developer with a background in laboratory science. Experienced at performing quality testing, working with a variety of team members, and focusing on client experience. Skilled at writing clean code to create beautiful and functional applications.

CONTACT INFORMATION

Kerrville, TX edowney.dev@gmail.com

www.emdowney.com https://www.linkedin.com/in/ emily-m-downey/

SKILLS & ABILITIES

- HTML/CSS
- Javascript
- MERN Stack
- Front-End Design
- Bootstrap Framework
- GitHub/Git Version Control
- User Experience
- Software Testing

PROJECTS

FaveFlix https://github.com/emilydowney/FaveFlix-Client

- Built a responsive movie web application using the MERN(MongoDB, Express, React, and Node.js) stack.
- Designed client-side features that allowed users to view and favorite different movies.

Pokédex https://github.com/emilydowney/js-app

 Created a Pokédex application using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript that loads data from an external API.

Events App https://github.com/emilydowney/events-app

 Coded a serverless, progressive web application (PWA) using React and test-driven development (TDD) to fetch calender events from the Google Calendar API.

EDUCATIONAL HISTORY

CareerFoundry

Full-Stack Web Development Program March-October 2021

University of North Texas

BS - Medical Laboratory Science August 2013-2017

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Peterson Health - Kerrville, TX

Medical Technologist (2019 - 2021)

- Completed quality control daily for dozens of .laboratory tests.
- Supervised 4 techs/phlebotomists on night shift and addressed any personnel or staffing issues.
- Monitored turn-around-time data for 6 blood bank employees and implemented improvement strategies.

Baylor Scott & White Health - Waco, TX

Med Tech Certified (2017-2019)

- Alternated working between 5 different departments and memorized hundreds of laboratory tests.
- Performed troubleshooting on 6 clinical instruments when errors occurred, including phone calls with customer support.
- Used 3 complex computer programs to report results, review patient history, and evaluate pending specimens.